Guide to the Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina Oral History Collection, 1981-2014 RL.11031
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Wilmington and surrounding areas, 1995-2007; undated; 9
  - Warshauer, Miriam, 2007; 220
    - Miriam Warshauer. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff and Lue Simopolous for Down Home project, 2007 June 15; transcript (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Warshauer, Sam, 2007; 221
    - Sam Warshauer. Interviewed for Down Home project, 2007 June 4; digital betacam (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-015)
- Winston-Salem and surrounding areas, 2006-2010; 10
  Geographic locations represented in this series include Hickory, Mount Airy, Statesville, and Winston-Salem, North Carolina.
  - Adler, Hanna and Howard (Statesville), 2007; 222
    - Hanna and Howard Adler. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 20; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-023)
      Container label: "Gordon Scrapyard - Statesville, Howard and Hannah [Hanna] Adler, Gene Lester Gordon, Temple Emanuel, Presbyterian Church, Gordon Hospice"
  - Brenner, Abe, 2006; 223
    - Abe Brenner. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 March 9; audiocassette (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-160)
      Container label: "Brenner"
    - Abe Brenner. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 April 24; audiocassette (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-127)
      Container label: "Abe Brenner"
    - Abe Brenner. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006; transcript (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Gelfand, Eve, 2007; 224
    - Eve Gelfand. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 June 8; audiocassette (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-037)
      Container label: "Eva [Eve] Gelfand"
    - Eve Gelfand. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 June 8; audiocassette (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-038)
      Container label: "Eve Gelfand"
  - Gordon, Barry (Statesville), 2008; 225
    - Barry Gordon. Interviewed by Liz Baker for Down Home project, 2008 February 17; transcript (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Gordon, Gene Lester (Statesville), 2007; 226
    - Gene Lester Gordon. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 20; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-023)
    - Gene Lester Gordon. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 20; transcript (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Gordon, Saul and Kalman (Statesville), 2007; 227
    - Saul and Kalman Gordon. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 20; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-022)
    - Saul and Kalman Gordon. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 20; transcript (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Reznick, Joseph, 2007; 229
    - Joseph Reznick. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 January 21; audiocassette (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-092)
      Container label: "Joe Reznick"
    - Joseph Reznick. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 January 21; transcript (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Schafer, Gerald (Mount Airy), circa 2010; 230
    - Gerald Schafer. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff, circa 2010; audiocassette (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-084)
      Container label: "Gerald Schafer"
    - Gerald Schafer. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff, circa 2010; transcript (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Schafer, Leon (Mount Airy), 2010; 231
    - Leon Schafer. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff, 2010 June 28; audiocassette, 1 of 2 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-050)
      Container label: "Leon Schafer"
    - Leon Schafer. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff, 2010 June 28; audiocassette, 2 of 2 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-053)
      Container label: "Leon Schaefer [Schafer]"
  - Zerden, Elaine, Marvin, and Howard (Hickory), circa 2008; 228
    - Elaine, Marvin, and Howard Zerden. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, circa 2008; audiocassette (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-016)
      Container label: "Marvin, Howard, Elaine Zerden"
- Oral history resources, circa 1986-2006
  This series consists of questionnaires, instructional packets, bibliographies, and related materials produced or collected in connection with the creation of the oral histories in this collection.
  Arrangement
  The materials in this series are arranged chronologically.
  - Durham-Chapel Hill community / Homelands oral history materials, circa 1986-1994 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Migrations oral history materials, circa 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Guides for conducting oral histories, 2002, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Down Home - materials related to organization of Greensboro oral history project, 2004-2005 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Down Home oral history packets, 2004-2006 (Box 9, Folder 11)